Man 1: Spring training camp and
he's definitely got the inside track.
Word is that they're having
some problems with injuries.
Man 2:
Really? Are they looking into...
Free-agent signings last second.
anything like that?
Man 1: Possibly. and they've got
a strong farm club too.
They've got some triple-a ballplayers
they might bring up.
Peter would certainly be able
to tell us more about that.
Man 2: Who do you like?
Man 1: So far.
[Like what I'm seeing in New York.
They've got a strong ball club. as usual.
That's in the American.
And in the national.
I'm still liking Chicago...
With a little bit of a twist here
for Los Angeles.
Man 2: Okay. so we're looking at
New York-Chicago world series...
Possible Los Angeles.
Man 1: Could be a dark horse.
Man 2: Hold him to it
at the end of the season.
That's gonna do it for us
from the sports desk.
- Back to the studio. Thanks. Dave.
- Man 1: Thanks for nothing. Eddie.
Man 3: Thank you. guys. That's not all we're
following. Here's Karen at the health desk.
The world of medicine
has seen its share of miracle cures...
From the polio vaccine
to heart transplants...
But all past achievements may pale in
comparison to the work of Dr. Alice krippin.
Thank you for joining us this morning.
- Not at all.
- 80. Dr. Krippin. give it to me in a nutshell.
Well. the premise is quite simple.
Take something designed by nature
and reprogram it...
To make it work for the body
rather than against it.
- We're talking about a virus?
- Yes.
In this case. the measles virus...
Which has been engineered at a genetic
level to be helpful rather than harmful.
Um. I'm not... I find the best way
to describe it is...
If you can imagine your body
as a highway...
And you picture the virus as a very fast
car being driven by a very bad man...
Imagine the damage that
that car could cause.
But then if you replace that man
with a cop...
The picture changes. And that's
essentially what we've done.
Now. how many people
have you treated so far?
Well. we've had 10.009 clinical trials
in humans so far.
- And how many are cancer-free?
- Ten thousand and nine.
So you have actually cured cancer?
Yes. yes. Yes. we have.
What you see? What you see?
Damn.
Let's go. Sam.
Come on.
Good morning. Matt.
It's looking great. I 7! Tell you.
Not only was this the biggest
snowstorm in New York City history...
It had to be one of the prettiest.
Imagine waking up on Sunday...
To 26.9 inches of snow
in New York City.
Robert:
Here you go. Just the way you like it.
Disgusting.
Excusg me. gxcusg me.
All right. Come on. relax.
Curry: However. it did strand
planes. trains and automobiles.
There was a report. a Turkish airlines
flight skidded off the runway at jfk.
No one was injured.
but for the most part. Matt...
There you go.
I'm gonna show you. attempting
the Bob hager rule of thumb here.
And I'm gonna plug my ruler in.
In New York. in 30 rock.
we have 16 inches of snow. Matt.
Back to you. Matt and Katie.
Gosh. All right. it looks great. It'll be
beautiful for the next day. at least.
- And then it turns brown.
- Couric: If that.
Anyway. Ann. thanks so much.
Mm-mm. No. no. no. Eat your vegetables.
Don't just push them around. eat them.
I'm not playing.
Woman: Good morning. This morning.
all up the east coast...
Okay. You gonna eat your vegetables.
We will sit down here all night.
The biggest challenge
is getting back to work.
What are you whining about?
Why didn't you just eat your vegetables?
Hey. All right. here's the deal.
Look. Look.
You're gonna eat twice as many vegetables
tomorrow night. All right?
Deal? Deal?
Come on.
Robert: Don't worry
about a thing
'cause every little thing
gonna be all right
I know that feels good.
Smiled with the rising sun
three little birds
ah. Sam.
Singin' sweet songs of melody...
I'm all right.
I'm all right. it's all right.
What's happening? I tried to reach you
on your cell. I get a recording.
- Cell service is down.
- Where are we going?
- Can't get used to the new regs.
- Robert: Going to aunt Sara's.
- Ma! No! Why?
- Baby. just strap yourself in. Go.
- Man: We're at 30 minutes. colonel.
- Copy.
- Thirty minutes to what?
- They're sealing off the island.
- Seal off the island? This island?
- But I don't wanna go to aunt Sara's.
Robert: Did you bring all the money?
Zoe: Yeah.
Robert: How much?
Zoe: Six hundred.
Why did you say. "you're going"?
- Robert: That's not enough.
- Robert.
You said. "you're going."
not. "we're going."
When you get across. I need you to get
to the atm. Get as much cash as you can.
Take Sara's car. go upstate.
I'll meet you at the farm.
Bring enough food for two weeks.
Jesus. Robert. did itjump?
Is it airborne?
Marley: But we only go to aunt Sara's
in the summer.
- It may be.
- Oh. my god.
- It's Christmas. What about my presents?
- He's announcing it.
President:
Make no mistake. Americans. this virus...
You left my Christmas presents
in the closet.
Hush now. mar.
Threatens the survival of not only our
nation. but of every other nation...
- Mommy. look. it's a butterfly.
- Marley. enough!
And so it is with great sadness.
but even greater resolve...
That tonight I have signed
an executive order...
Initiating a military quarantine
of New York City.
God be with us.
Announcer:
This has been a special...
The window is still open. We find
something in a week or two weeks...
We can reverse the spread.
I can still fix this.
Please. You can do the same work
outside the city.
This is ground zero. This is my site.
We talked about this.
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
I'm not gonna let this happen.
Let? This isn't up to you.
You can't control...
Marley:
Ah! Daddy. it's a monster!
Robert: How'd you sleep?
Look out. Come on.
you know better than that.
Dr. Robert Neville. September 5th. 2012.
ga series. serum 391.
Animal trials. Streaming video.
Ga series results appear typical.
Compounds 1. 3. 4. 6. 8. 9. 10...
11. 14. 16. 18 did not kill the virus.
Compounds 2. 5. 7...
12.13.15.17...
Hold on a second.
Compound 6 appears to be showing
decreased aggression response.
Partial pigmentation return.
Slight pupil constriction.
Ga series. serum 391. compound 6...
Next candidate for human trials.
You hang in there. number six.
Yeah. that's what you want.
Good morning. Marge.
Good morning. Fred.
What are you guys doing here so early?
That's a nice sweatshirt there. Fred.
Don't set it down anywhere.
I'll see you guys inside.
What's happening. buddy?
Good morning. Hank.
I'm midway through the g's.
Hey. who's the girl in...?
Never mind.
Hey. I'll see you in the morning.
What am I supposed to say?
Wanna see some infected rats?"
Okay. tomorrow.
I'm gonna say hello tomorrow.
Come here. Hey. Hey.
Good job. You did so good.
Yes. Yes.
Ah.
Look at that. See that? Red salmon.
Wow. actual spam. Yeah.
You'll get some of that later.
Let's go.
Robert:
My name is Robert Neville.
I am a survivor living in New York City.
I am broadcasting on all am frequencies.
I will be at the south street seaport
every day at midday...
When the sun is highest in the sky.
If you are out there...
If anyone is out there...
I can provide food.
I can provide shelter.
I can provide security.
If there's anybody out there...
Anybody...
Please.
You are not alone.
Fore!
Keep your eye on this one for me.
I'm getting good.
Ss-ss.
Sam! No. no. no!
No! No! Sam!
Hello. Sam?
Come on. Sam.
I gotta go. Sam.
I gotta go. I gotta go.
Sam. Sam.
Sam. Sam. come on. we gotta go.
Sam.
What are you doing?
Sam. we gotta go!
Sam. go! Go!
Sam. get out! Get out!
You gotta pay attention. okay?
You gotta pay attention.
Listen. uh...
I want you to stay here
on this one. okay?
Because you can still get infected.
And I can't.
So. look. if I'm not back by dark...
Just go.
Okay. Subject is female.
Likely 18 to 20 years of age.
Dilaudid push only sedates effectively
at six times human dose.
Core temperature. 106 fahrenheit.
Pulse. 200 bpm.
Respiration elevated.
Pa 02. 300 percent of normal.
Pupils fully dilated.
Nonreactive to light.
Extreme reaction to uv exposure.
Symptoms and tissue samples
confirm subject is infected with kv.
Vaccine test.
Ga series. serum 391. compound 6.
Commencing human trials.
Respiration slowing.
Pulse. 190. Core temperature...
105...
104 and decreasing.
We may have something here.
Ga series. serum 391. compound 6
ineffective on humans.
Test results linked to this entry
saved on six redundant drives.
Still no cure.
Robert: Day 1001.
We came in close contact
with a hive today.
Blood tests confirm that
I remain immune to both the airborne...
And contact strains.
Canines remain immune
to airborne strain only.
You can't go running
into the dark. dummy.
Vaccine trials continue.
I'm still unable to transfer my immunity
to infected hosts.
The krippin virus is...
Elegant.
Just fishing in the dark. son.
Mm. A behavioral note. um:
An infected male
exposed himself to sunlight today.
Now. it's possible
decreased brain function...
Or the growing scarcity of food
is causing them to...
Ignore their basic survival instincts.
Social de-evolution appears complete.
Typical human behavior
is now entirely absent.
Why are we stopping?
The street's closed. folks. We hoof it.
- We got less than 10 minutes.
- Baby. give me the dog.
- Come on. baby. Let's go. Let's go.
- Marley: Daddy!
It's all right. It's all right. Come on.
Mike: Keep the colonel and his family
between us and don't let anyone stop you.
Marley: Mommy. they have guns!
It's okay. They're in the army like daddy.
Man 1:
Unless you have clearance...
You cannot pass the checkpoint.
Please return to your homes.
Mike: Make a hole. make a hole!
Coming through!
Man 1: Unless you have clearance.
you cannot pass the checkpoint.
Please return to your homes.
Man 2: You're clear. Move ahead.
You're clear.
Man 3:
All right. that's it. move up.
All right. step up.
You're clear. Next. Let's go.
No good.
Man 4:
Military quarantine is about to begin.
Man 5: Come on. step back.
- Military quarantine is about to begin.
- Look. look. look.
Woman: I'm not infected.
Man 2: Clear. Good. go on.
I'm not infected.
Please! Please!
- Please take my baby. Take my baby. please.
- Man 5: You're gonna have to move back.
- No good.
- Man 6: Follow me. ma'am.
Zoe: What? No! Robert! Robert!
Get your hands off my wife.
Get your hands off.
Mommy! Mike: Stand down.
Lieutenant...
- Mommy!
- Scan her again. Get your hands off of her!
Get your hands off of my wife.
- Mike: Stand down!
- Scan her again. Stand down!
Stand down. soldier! Stand down!
I am lieutenant colonel Robert Neville.
I am ordering you to scan her again.
Scan her again!
All right. scan her again.
- It's clear.
- It's clear. Move through.
Who's next? Come on.
Take my baby with you!
Please! Please!
- Mommy!
- Please take my baby. Please!
Daddy. why can't the little girl come too?
Man 4:
Stay away from the shoreline.
How long?
Five minutes. We'll make it.
This is ranger 621. we're on site.
Military quarantine is about to begin.
I won't take my eyes off them. colonel.
You got my word on it.
Robert: Give me a kiss.
[Love you. [Love you.
Dear lord. please watch over Robert...
And keep him strong
through the struggles ahead.
Lord. please just bring him home safely.
Amen.
Daddy's gonna make the monsters
go away. baby. okay?
Sam. you protect daddy.
- No. baby. I can't. Daddy can't take a dog.
- Man 7: Sir. we gotta go!
Daddy. look. it's a butterfly.
It's a butterfly.
All right. come on. let's go!
How'd you sleep?
Dr. Neville will be taking a closer look
at the ongoing mutations...
Of Dr. Alice krippin's once-hailed
miracle cure for cancer.
So far. almost 5000 patients
treated with her retrofitted virus...
Have begun exhibiting symptoms
resembling the early onset of rabies.
Twenty-five patients have already died.
Dr. Neville has ordered local hospitals
to stockpile antiviral drugs...
And to begin
preliminary quarantine protocols.
It's my birthday.
We are fully confident Dr. Neville
can see us through these...
You gonna sing?
Robert:
My name is Robert Neville.
I am a survivor living in New York City.
I am broadcasting on all am frequencies.
I will be at the south street seaport
every day at midday...
When the sun is highest in the sky.
If you are out there.
if anyone is out there...
I can provide food. I can provide shelter.
I can provide security.
If there's anybody out there. anybody...
Please.
You are not alone.
Listen. uh...
If you're planning a party or something.
just tell me now.
Okay? Because you know
I don't like surprises.
And I swear I'll act surprised. Okay?
Hey! Hey!
What the hell
are you doing out here. Fred?!
What the...? What the hell are you...?
No!
What the hell
are you doing out here. Fred?!
How did you get out here?!
Fred. if you're real.
you better tell me right now!
If you're real.
Damn it. Fred!
Damn it!
I'm all right. I'm all
right. I'm all right.
Baby. I'm okay.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Let's go.
Eh. eh! Come on. Sam. come on.
Let's go! Sam!
No! No! Let's go!
We gotta go home. Sam. Let's go!
It's okay.
You're all right. Okay. It's okay.
You're all right. You're all right.
Samantha? Samantha. look at me. girl.
Hey. You're okay.
You're okay. Samantha.
We just gotta get you home.
Gotta get you... gotta take you home.
Let me take you home.
All right. come here.
Come here. Come here. Come here.
Come on. Come here. Come here.
I got you. I got you.
It's okay.
You're okay.
Don't worry
about a thing
'cause every little thing
is gonna be all right
don't worry about a thing
rise up this morning
smiled with the rising sun
I promised my friend...
That I would say hello to you today.
Please say hello to me.
Woman: Come on! Stay with me!
Where do you live?
Hey.
Stay with me.
Where do you live?
Robert: Uh...
11 Washington square.
They don't know where I live.
Don't... don't let them track us.
You gotta stay out till dawn.
Man: Donkey?
What are you doing?
I would think of all people you would
recognize a wall when you see one.
Well. yeah. But the wall's supposed to go
around my swamp. not through it.
Donkey: It is. Around your half. see?
That's your half. this is my half.
Shrek: Oh. your half? Hm.
Donkey: Yes. my half.
I helped rescue the Princess. I did
half the work. [Get half the Booty.
Now hand me that big old rock.
the one that looks like your head.
Shrek: Back offi
donkey: No. you back off.
Shrek: This is my swamp!
Donkey: Our swamp.
Smelly ogre. Shrek: Fine!
Donkey: Come back.
I'm not through with you!
Shrek:
Well. I'm through with you.
Donkey: You know. with you
it's always "me. me. me."
Well. guess what. now it's my turn.
So you just shut up and pay attention!
You are mean to me! You insult me and
you don't appreciate anything that I do.
You're always pushing me around
or pushing me away.
Oh. yeah? Well. if I treated you so bad.
how come you came back?
Donkey: Because that's what friends do!
They forgive each other!
Shrek: Oh. yeah.
You're right. donkey. I forgive you...
For stabbing me in the back!
Donkey: You're so wrapped up in layers.
you're afraid of your own feelings.
Shrek: Go away. Donkey: See?
Doing it again.
just like you did to Fiona...
And all she did was like you.
maybe love you.
Shrek: Love me? She said I was ugly.
a hideous creature.
I heard the two of you talking.
Donkey: She wasn't talking about you.
she was talking about somebody else.
I'm afraid the eggs are powdered.
Obviously you know that.
They're yours.
But I did find bacon. which is about
the most fantastic thing in history.
And some antibiotics in the bathroom.
I put by your plate.
because your leg is okay...
But it won't be for very long
if you don't start a course soon.
Robert: Who are you?
Anna: I'm Anna and that's Ethan.
Don't let it get cold.
It's okay. Go on.
We came from Maryland.
We heard your message on the radio.
We were at the pier at noon.
We waited all day.
We're going to Vermont.
To the survivors' colony.
What?
In bethel. It's a safe zone.
There's no survivors' colony.
there's no safe zones.
Nothing happened
the way it was supposed to.
Nothing worked
In the mountains. There's a whole colony
of people there who didn't get sick.
The virus couldn't survive the cold.
There's a colony...
Robert: Shut up! Shut up!
Everybody's dead.
Everybody is dead.
I just need...
I need a minute. Okay?
I just... I was saving that bacon.
I was saving it.
I'm just... I'm gonna go upstairs.
All right? Just...
I'm gonna go.
Ethan. put the knife down.
Man: You there! Ogre.
Shrek: Aye.
Man:
By the order of lord farquaad...
I am authorized
to place you both under arrest...
And transport you
to a designated resettlement facility.
Oh. really? You and what army?
Can I say something to you?
You was really. really something
back there. Incredible.
Are you talking to...
Me?
Yes. I was talking to you.
You was really great back there.
Those guards. they thought they was
all that. You showed up. and barn!
Tripping over themselves
like babes in the woods.
That really made me
feel good to see that.
That's great. Really.
Man. it's good to be free.
Now. why don't you go celebrate
your freedom with your own friends?
But. uh...
I don't have any friends.
And I'm not going out there by myself.
Wait a minute. I got a great idea.
I'll stick with you!
Donkey:
You a mean. green fighting machine.
Together we 'il scare the spit
out of anybody that crosses us.
I like Shrek.
Donkey: That was really scary.
If you don't mind me saying...
If that don't work. your breath
will get the job done...
Because you definitely need some
tic tacs. because your breath stinks!
Man. you almost burned the hair
out of my nose. Just like the time...
You're not so good with people anymore.
are you?
Thank you for my leg.
Okay.
Where have you been?
I was on a red cross evacuation ship
out of 8510 Paulo.
Those boats
weren't meant to be permanent.
No. they weren't.
When the Navy fell apart.
we started docking to take on supplies.
Someone picked it up on shore.
Five of us were immune.
You said five?
The darkseekers got them.
You are the Robert Neville. aren't you?
It's too late today.
If we leave tomorrow at dawn. we can
make it to Vermont in a straight shot.
- So if you had...
- I'm not leaving.
This is ground zero.
This is my site.
I'm not gonna let this happen.
I can still fix this.
- Robert: Whoa. You scared me.
- Sorry.
I called down twice.
Oh. Oh. thank you.
It's heavily sedated.
Don't worry. it's safe.
I've never seen one so still.
They're always biting.
You think that can cure her?
Um... no. this will
almost certainly kill it...
But it's possible by drastically
reducing the body temperature...
I can increase the compound's
effectiveness.
Did all of them die?
Anna: My god.
God didn't do this. Anna. we did.
Where can Ethan sleep?
He's heavy.
Can you get that?
She's beautiful.
What's her name?
Marley.
- Her name was Marley.
- It's a beautiful name.
Yeah. We named her after Bob Marley.
- Who?
- Uh. the singer.
Damian?
Uh. his father.
His father.
Nope.
I shot the sheriff
but I didn't shoot the deputy
- Oh. that is unacceptable.
- What?
Best album ever made.
- You don't recognize that?
- Mm-mm.
He had this idea.
it was kind of a virologist's idea.
He believed that you could cure
racism and hate. Literally cure it...
By injecting music and love
into people's lives.
One day. he was scheduled
to perform at a peace rally.
Gunmen came to his house
and shot him down.
Two days later...
He walked out on that stage and sang.
Somebody asked him why.
He said. "the people...
Who are trying to make this world worse
are not taking a day off.
How can I?"
Light up the darkness.
Come with us. Neville.
To the colony.
There's no colony. Anna.
Everything just fell apart.
- There was no evacuation plan...
- You're wrong. There is a colony.
I know. okay?
How do you know. Anna?
I just know.
How? I said. how do you know?
How could you know?
God told me.
He has a plan.
- God told you?
- Yes.
- The god?
- I know how this sounds.
- It sounds crazy.
But something told me
to turn on the radio.
Something told me to come here.
My voice on the radio
told you to come here. Anna.
You were trying to kill yourself
last night?
Anna.
I got here just in time to save your life.
That's a coincidence?
- Just stop it. Stop it. Stop.
- He must have sent me here for a reason.
Neville. the world is quieter now.
You just have to listen.
If we listen...
We can hear god's plan.
- God's plan?
- Yeah.
All right. Let me tell you
about your god's plan.
There were 6 billion people on earth
when the infection hit.
Kv had a 90 percent kill rate.
That's 5.4 billion...
People dead.
Crashed and bled out. dead.
Less than 1 percent immunity.
That left 12 million healthy people
like you. me and Ethan.
The other 588 million...
Turned into your darkseekers.
And then they got hungry.
And they killed and fed on everybody.
Everybody!
Every single person
that you or I has ever known...
Is dead!
There is no god. There is no god.
What is that?
Was it still dark when you
brought us home last night?
You were bleeding.
There was light on the horizon.
Turn the light off. Turn it off.
They followed us home.
Shit.
Anna.
Anna!
Come on. Come on.
- Are you okay? You all right?
- Anna: Yeah.
Are you all right?
- You okay?
- Oh. my god. You're bleeding.
Go to the lab. Downstairs. go!
Get to the lab! To the lab!
Get behind the plexi.
Oh. my god. Come on.
Come on. it's okay. It's okay.
Oh. my god.
It's working.
Neville...
No! Stop! Stop!
Look. look. look. I can save you.
I can sa... I can help you.
You are sick and I can help you.
I can... I can fix this!
I can save everybody!
I can fix everything! It's working.
It's working!
Stop! Stop!
Let me save you! Let me save you!
No. no!
Marley:
Daddy. look. it's a butterfly.
- What are you doing?
- The cure is in her blood.
Coal chute. I think it'll be safe.
Ethan. get in!
- Go.
- Come on. get in.
- Get in.
- Anna.
I think this is why you're here.
What are you doing?
I'm listening.
- Neville. there's room. Come!
- No.
They're not gonna stop.
Stay in till dawn.
Anna: In 2009. a deadly virus
burned through our civilization...
Pushing humankind
to the edge of extinction.
Dr. Robert Neville dedicated his life...
To the discovery of a cure...
And the restoration of humanity.
On September 9th. 2012...
At approximately 8:49 pm...
He discovered that cure.
And at 8:52. he gave his life to defend it.
We are his legacy.
This is his legend.
Light up the darkness.
Subtitles by sdi media group